# KARL FINKEL

### **SUMMARY STATEMENT**

A former Project Coordinator with 3+ years of experience in the project management field turned Full Stack Web Developer. I am looking to enter a new field. With about a year of undirected coding experience along with 3 months of formal education at the University of Austin Texas Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp. I am looking for an opportunity to put my newfound development skills to work.

# **C**ERTIFICATIONS

- NACE Cathodic Protection Technician I Certification 2018
- Certified Associate Project Management (CAPM) PMI Certification 2022
- University of Texas Austin Full Stack Web Development Certification-2023

# **WORK HISTORY**

**Project Coordinator**, 03/2020 - 01/2023 **Lake Superior Consulting (LSC) -** Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Performed Project Coordination and management duties for one large and several smaller clients that rely on LSC's Integrity Management team.
- Managed a team of several technicians over five lines of business spanning several states.
- Built out and maintained workbooks for project work that include: Proposals, Contacts, Budgets, Schedules, Scope of work, Change orders, Deliverables, WBS, and Lessons learned.
- Managed projects through the entirety of its lifecycle.
- Created Microsoft Teams and SharePoint pages for client groups within the organization to promote a more streamlined and open working environment for client teams.

# Cathodic Protection Technician NACE CP I Field Lead, 06/2018 - 03/2020 Lake Superior Consulting (LSC) - Duluth, Minnesota

- Provided project completion safely and on schedule, accurate and timely data gathering for indirect surveys
- Worked on CP design and field testing, construction installations, reporting and inspections.
- Additional responsibilities included internal project quality assigned by supervisory staff to ensure maintenance of LSC equipment/calibrations, vehicles, and office space.
- Expanded corrosion-related knowledge base and industry regulations.

**Civil Consultant Intern (Financial Crimes Investigation Unit)** 04/2017 - 08/2017

**Duluth Police Department - Duluth, MN** 



# CONTACT

**Location:** Austin, TX **Phone:** 952-715-1910

Email: kmanfinkel17@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kar

l-finkel-188a83199/

Github:

https://github.com/Meister7K

#### SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suites, specifically in SharePoint webpage apps and Excel.
- Respectable formal writing and people skills
- Solid financial understanding and budget management ability
- Scheduling and resource management skills
- SCRUM & Agile frameworks
- Strong communication skills
- Flexible problem-solving skills
- Strong at prioritizing tasks and breaking down projects into small manageable pieces.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages & Frameworks
  - o HTML
- o CSS
- o JavaScript

- Learned the internal operations of a police department.
- Worked in Excel to record, look up, and report on data obtained in financial cases.
- Reviewed copious amounts of financial documents and learned to spot discrepancies through continuous reviews. Peer reviewed search warrants and other documents.
- Learned how to use police sponsored communication skills to effectively connect with all audiences. Met and communicated with a diverse community. Worked with a team of investigators on many financial cases.
- Solidified the values of teamwork and the importance of planning and communication with multiple team members.

- o mySQL
- o React.js
- o Bootstrap
- o node.js
- o express.js
- o Bootstrap

#### Platforms

- o Github
- o VS Code
- o MongoDB
- o Insomnia

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Coding Bootcamp**

University of Texas Austin - Austin, TX

March 2023 - June 2023

#### Bachelor's degree

University of Minnesota-Duluth - Duluth MN

- Bachelor of Arts in Criminology
- Minor in Accounting
- Collegiate Athlete: Football 2013-18 Graduated May 2018

# **High School Diploma**

Lakeville North High School - Lakeville, MN

June 2013

# INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Renewable Energy
- Human Longevity
- Education Methodology
- coding

#### LICENSES

• Driver's License Class D with Motorcycle endorsement

# Awards and Honors

- Football All NSIC Conference 1st Team 2015, 16, 17
- University of Minnesota Dean's List Honors 2017,18